
export const quizQuestions_9 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of performance optimization in React applications?',
      choices: [
        'To make the code more readable.',
        'To enhance user experience by improving application speed and responsiveness.',
        'To reduce the file size of the application.',
        'None of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To enhance user experience by improving application speed and responsiveness.'
    },
    {
      question: 'What is memoization in React?',
      choices: [
        'A technique used to optimize component rendering by caching the result of a function.',
        'A method to prevent components from rendering.',
        'A way to validate user inputs in React forms.',
        'None of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'A technique used to optimize component rendering by caching the result of a function.'
    },
    {
      question: 'How can lazy loading be implemented in React applications?',
      choices: [
        'By postponing the loading of entire components until they are needed.',
        'By completely removing components from the application.',
        'Lazy loading is not supported in React.',
        'None of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'By postponing the loading of entire components until they are needed.'
    },
    {
      question: 'What is code splitting in React?',
      choices: [
        'A technique to optimize code by removing unnecessary comments.',
        'Breaking down the application code into smaller chunks that can be loaded on demand.',
        'Splitting the code into multiple files for better organization.',
        'None of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'Breaking down the application code into smaller chunks that can be loaded on demand.'
    },
    {
      question: 'How does React.lazy() contribute to code splitting in React?',
      choices: [
        'It enables dynamic loading of components with lazy evaluation.',
        'It removes unused code from the application.',
        'It breaks down the entire codebase into smaller files.',
        'None of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'It enables dynamic loading of components with lazy evaluation.'
    },
    {
      question: 'What does the React Profiler tool provide for performance analysis in React?',
      choices: [
        'It provides a visual representation of component hierarchy.',
        'It measures the time it takes for components to render.',
        'It offers suggestions for code optimization.',
        'All of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'All of the above'
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of shouldComponentUpdate lifecycle method in performance optimization?',
      choices: [
        'To skip rendering a component if certain conditions are met.',
        'To force rendering of a component regardless of changes.',
        'To handle asynchronous operations efficiently.',
        'None of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To skip rendering a component if certain conditions are met.'
    },
    {
      question: 'What are some strategies for optimizing React applications?',
      choices: [
        'Minimizing component re-renders, using memoization, and code splitting.',
        'Increasing the number of components in the application.',
        'Using only class components instead of functional components.',
        'None of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'Minimizing component re-renders, using memoization, and code splitting.'
    },
    {
      question: 'How does React.memo() contribute to performance optimization?',
      choices: [
        'It prevents unnecessary re-renders of functional components.',
        'It optimizes HTTP requests in React applications.',
        'It enables lazy loading of components.',
        'None of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'It prevents unnecessary re-renders of functional components.'
    },
    {
      question: 'What role does the use of keys play in optimizing React rendering?',
      choices: [
        'Keys are not used for performance optimization in React.',
        'They help React identify which items have changed, are added, or are removed.',
        'Keys are used to compress the codebase.',
        'None of the above'
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'They help React identify which items have changed, are added, or are removed.'
    },
  ]  
}